A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Real Estate, Series L FA321
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Cleveland Property
  - Cleveland Property - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    Photographs of Cleveland scenes, City Homestead.
  - Cleveland Property - Mittleberger Property, 1894-1920; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    Gift to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; leased to Miss Mittelberger as school. Valuation and appraisal; lease to Conleys; fire on property. Renewal of lease; razing of building; deed to Lawida Corporation. Correspondents include Augusta Mittelberger, C. E. Terrill, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., N. A. Quilling, Starr J. Murphy, H. D. Sims.
  - Cleveland Property - Mittleberger Property, 1921-1938; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Cleveland Property - Morgan Property, 1909-1940; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    Lease of property for automobile salesroom; erection of new building; assignment of lease to Lucas & Christensen. Deed to Lawida Corporation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy, Robert W. Gumbel, J. Schlitz, J. C. Jones, C. E. Terrill.
  - Cleveland Property - Morgan Property, 1909-1940; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Cleveland Property - Morgan Property - Euclid Avenue Church, Sale to, 1922-1946 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    Fire in building adjoining church; sale of property to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Payment terms; time extension; razing of building; payment of property taxes. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Rev. W. W. Bustard, J. C. Jones, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, Robert W. Gumbel, S. H. Holding.
  - Cleveland Property - Morgan Property - Lease to Gould, 1923-1936 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    Lease of property; razing of building; property used as parking space. Rental arrangements. Correspondents include M. G. Gould, J. C. Jones, Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley, Robert W. Gumbel, Joseph Schlitz.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Superior and West 6th Street, 1910-1912 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    Photographs of building; plats of property.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Hirsch Building, 1912-1913 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    Purchase of property adjoining Rockefeller Building; alterations to building; lease to National City Bank.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - General Correspondence, 1912-1919 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    Terrill appointed agent; audit of books; collection of rentals. Book values of property; addition to 11th floor for building.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Kirby Suit, 1920-1924 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    Lease problems.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Sale, 1912-1920 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    Sale of property; appraisal. Correspondents include H. D. Sims, Charles O. Heydt, J. C. Jones, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Phillip Keebler, C. E. Terrill.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Sale - C. E. Terrill Correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    Kirby suit; trouble over payment of salary and commission to Terrill in sale of building; termination of employment.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Sale - Kirby's Offer, 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    Offer to purchase property; negotiations; rejection of bid. Kirby suit against John D. Rockefeller, Jr. alleging failure to perform.
  - Cleveland Property - Sale of Rockefeller Building - Terrill Suit, 1912-1924 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    Terrill's claims for broker's commission on Kirby and Jones transactions and for unpaid salary; revocation of power of attorney to Terrill; settlement of case. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Boulware, S. E. Wenger, J. C. Jones, S. H. Holding.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building, 1912-1953 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    Gift to Miss Wenger; rechristening of building as "Rockefeller Building." Death of Terrill; Ralph Coe's newspaper articles on the building. Correspondents include James C. Jones, Charles O. Heydt, Lilly E. Wenger, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Cleveland Property - Rockefeller Building - Cleveland Discount Company, 1922-1926 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    Failure of company which purchase building.
  - Cleveland Property - Standard Block, 1898-1911; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    Extension of Standard Oil Company lease; lease to Strauss Brothers Company; Building's structural defects; failure of Strauss Brothers. Conveyance of property from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Abeyton Realty Company; lease to W. H. Price; assignment to the Smythe Building Company. Taxes; payment of rent; conveyance to Lawida Corporation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Frederick T. Gates, L. M. Bowers, Charles O. Heydt, A. B. Smythe, N. A. Quilling, W. H. Price.
  - Cleveland Property - Standard Block, 1912-1940; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Cleveland Property - Cleveland Taxes, 1916-1941 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    Taxes on Cleveland, Cleveland Heights, and E. Cleveland properties; assessments levied, refunds paid. Correspondents include C. E. Terrill, A. L. Boulware, Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, J. C. Jones, S. H. Holding.
  - Cleveland Property - Taxes, 1923-1930; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Cleveland Property - Taxes, 1931-1938; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Cleveland Property - Taxes, Heydt, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Cleveland Property - Woodland Avenue Block, 1898-1925 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    Valuation of land; collection of rents, sale of property. Correspondents include Winthrop Aldrich, C. E. Terrill, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, J. G. W. Cowles.
- Ashton Realty Company
  - Ashton Realty Company, 1928-1930; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    Organized to carry out John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s program for purchase of land to protect the Palisades - a New Jersey real estate company. Purchases of property through Ashton and several subsidiaries; descriptions of financing; liquidation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, J. A. Osbourne, Charles O. Heydt.
    215
  - Ashton Realty Company, 1930-1932; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Ashton Realty Company, 1932-1937; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Ashton Realty Company, 1938-1950; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Ashton Realty Company - Property Appraisals, 1934-1938 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    Made by New Jersey real estate operators, 1934-1935.
  - Ashton Realty Company - Letters to Corporations Buying Property, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Ashton Realty Company - Transfer to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1939-1944; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased lands from real estate companies in Tenafly, Alpine, Norwood, Englewood and Cresskill, New Jersey, in 1939, for $1,800,000; this ended property holdings through those companies. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler.
    215.1
  - Ashton Realty Company - Transfer to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1939-1944; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 91)
- Degnon Realty and Terminal Company
  - Degnon Realty and Terminal Company, 1905-1953 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., subscribed $10,000 to Long Island real estate development promoted by friends; carried without John D. Rockefeller, Jr. control. 1911 dividend; after 1929 received 160% return of investment through liquidating dividends. Stock given to Sealantic Fund, 1947. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler.
- Empire Mortgage Company
  - Empire Mortgage Company, 1921-1953 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    Owned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to hold his real estate; run by Thomas M. Debevoise and Charles O. Heydt; routine office matters.
    189
  - Empire Mortgage Company - Transfer of Property to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1930-1938 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    Letters transmitting deeds for recording.
- Realty Advisory Board on Labor Relations
  - Realty Advisory Board on Labor Relations, 1934-1936 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    Handled owners' collective bargaining duties in dealing with unions; ran employment agency; John D. Rockefeller Jr. and estate managers belonged to Board.
- Itasca Lands
  - Itasca Lands - Minnesota Property, 1903-1948 (Box 18, Folder 96)
    Belonged to John D. Rockefeller, Sr., given to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; payment of taxes, sale of timber. Attempts to sell; gift to state of Minnesota, 1948. Correspondents include E. V. Cary, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    69
- Lawida Corporation
  - Lawida Corporation, 1935-1952 (Box 18, Folder 97)
    Set up in 1935; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave corporation real estate and stock, received Lawida stock in exchange. New York and Cleveland real estate; management; dissolution. Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and Winthrop Rockefeller beneficiaries of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s actions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt.
    91
  - Lawida Corporation, 1935-1952 (Box 18, Folder 0097A)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and Winthrop Rockefeller beneficiaries of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s actions. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Lawida Corporation - Transfer of Property to Corporation, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 98)
  - Lawida Corporation - Balance Sheets - Income Estimates, 1936-1947 (Box 18, Folder 99)
- Midtown Development and Investment Corporation
  - Midtown Development and Investment Corporation, 1930-1935 (Box 18, Folder 100)
    Organized to hold real estate and securities in one place to even out income tax during development of Rockefeller Center; relations with Center; management of securities. Incorporated in New Jersey; local tax problems. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    240
  - Midtown Development and Investment Corporation - Dissolution & Transfer of Stock to Rockefeller Center, 1939-1944 (Box 18, Folder 101)
  - Midtown Development and Investment Corporation - Financial Reports, 1931-1950 (Box 18, Folder 102)
  - Midtown Development and Investment Corporation - Appraisal of Stock Holdings, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 103)
    Appraisals of property underlying stock of Midtown and its subsidiaries.
- New York Property
  - New York Property - General, 1926-1942; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 104)
    General policy questions on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s New York real estate holdings. Offers of property declined; collection of scrap metal for war effort. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, F. Staley, Thomas M. Debevoise, C. E. Siegesmund, Phillip Keebler.
  - New York Property - General, 1944-1961; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 105)
  - New York Property - Insurance, 1941-1943 (Box 19, Folder 106)
    Fire, plate glass, war damage policies. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, F. Staley, B. Turnbull.
  - New York Property - Appraisals, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 107)
    Douglas Gibbons appraisals of 49th-53rd and 54th Street properties.
  - New York Property - H. Robertson, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 108)
    Handles rental and sale of Fifth Avenue property between 52nd and 53rd Streets through Rockefeller Center, Inc. real estate office. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, H. Robertson, Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - East 66th and Third Avenue; 1260 Second Avenue, 1927-1939 (Box 19, Folder 109)
    Purchased to protect Institute; traded to New York Trade School.
  - New York Property - Avenue A and 67th Street, Northwest Corner, 1923-1933 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    Bought to prevent public garage being built in vicinity of Rockefeller Institute; rented as ice skating area. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - First Avenue-67th & 68th Street, New York Trade School, 1924-1934 (Box 19, Folder 111)
    Purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to give to Cancer Hospital. Gift of hospital delayed. Management of property. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - General, 1930-1936 (Box 19, Folder 112)
    Plans for property. Insurance. Transfer to Rockefeller Institute. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - Maps & Data regarding Cost, [1935] (Box 19, Folder 113)
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - #404, 1927-1929 (Box 19, Folder 114)
    Purchased to protect Rockefeller Institute. Buildings demolished. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - #406-408, 1930-1934 (Box 19, Folder 115)
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - #410-416, 1929-1933 (Box 19, Folder 116)
    Purchased to protect Rockefeller Institute. Rental of property. Buildings demolished. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - #418-424, 1927-1931 (Box 20, Folder 117)
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - #426, 428, 430, 1923-1933 (Box 20, Folder 118)
  - New York Property - East 68th Street - #434 (New York Hospital Property), 1928-1930 (Box 20, Folder 119)
    Bought for Cancer hospital. Paid $249,121.14. Buildings demolished. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - East 68th-69th Street, Second and Third Avenue, 1928-1940; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 120)
    Purchase of entire block to protect Rockefeller Institute. Plan for model apartments. Rental of old buildings through Douglas Gibbons & Company. Called the Normandy Realty Block. Repairs. Given to Memorial Hospital, June 1, 1947. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, H. P. Fish, A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - East 68th-69th Street, Second and Third Avenue, 1941-1949; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 121)
  - New York Property - East 68th-69th Streets - Appraisals (Frank Vought, Inc.), 1938-1939 (Box 20, Folder 122)
    N. Frank Vought, Inc. appraisals of Normandy properties.
  - New York Property - 44 East 76th Street, 1956-1958 (Box 20, Folder 123)
    Purchased from Dr. John H. Richards by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Leased back to Dr. Richards. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made the doctor an annual gift to cover cost of lease. Repairs. Preparations to sell house in 1958 when Dr. Richards moved out. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John H. Richards, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - 44 East 76th Street - Sale to Miss Hewitt, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 124)
    Terms of sale.
  - New York Property - Fifth Avenue - 666 Construction, 1922-1941 (Box 20, Folder 125)
    W. K. Vanderbilt home. Purchased as an investment. Building demolished. Replaced by new structure for furrier. Problems of construction. Offers to buy property. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - Fifth Avenue - 666 Construction - A. J. Thomas Correspondence, 1928 (Box 20, Folder 126)
    Payments for architectural services.
  - New York Property - 666 Fifth Avenue - Gunther Lease, 1927-1936; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 127)
    Lease arrangements, costs of reconditioning. Tenant desires. Compromise. Reductions in rent in 1932, 1933, 1934. New lease, 1937. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - 666 Fifth Avenue - Gunther Lease, 1937-1946, (31); Folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 128)
  - New York Property - 666 Fifth Avenue - Gunther Lease - Lease Amendment, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 129)
    Documents.
  - New York Property - 666-670 Fifth Avenue - Sale (to Fifty-Fifty Second Corporation), 1945-1947 (Box 21, Folder 130)
    Sale to Fifth Fifty-Second Corporation. Terms cash. Lord and Taylor interest in land. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - 666-670 Fifth Avenue - General, 1929-1940; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 131)
    Management of property. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 666-670 Fifth Avenue - General, 1940-1946; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 132)
    Building management. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 666-670 Fifth Avenue - Purchase, 1922-1925 (Box 21, Folder 133)
    Purchased as an investment.
  - New York Property - 668 Fifth Avenue - Lanz, Inc., 1940-1946 (Box 21, Folder 134)
    Tenant. Retail-wholesale clothes outlet. Upkeep, repairs, lease revisions. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases, 1932-1948 (Box 22, Folder 135)
    Analysis of leases. Building management. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Chipman, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 136)
    Tenant.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Durlacher Brothers, Stora Art Galleries, 1930-1940 (Box 22, Folder 137)
    Tenant in arrears.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Arthur C. Holden, Emergency Exchange Plan, 1932-1943 (Box 22, Folder 138)
    Area provided for relief work. Tenant in arrears.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Fred Eldean, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 139)
    Public Relations tenant.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Folk Art Center, 1939-1945 (Box 22, Folder 140)
    Tenant. Family interest in Center.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Hofstatter & Company, 1927-1940 (Box 22, Folder 141)
    Reductions in rent.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Harlow, Keppel, & Company, 1940-1943 (Box 22, Folder 142)
    Rental agreement.
  - New York Property - 668-670 Fifth Avenue - Leases - Lehne, Richard W., 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 143)
  - New York Property - 670 Fifth Avenue - Raymond Whitcomb Lease, 1929-1943 (Box 22, Folder 144)
    Lessee sublets parts of building to other tenants. Rent arrears. Stock issue to cover debts. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in rent arrears and stock. Assigned to Sealantic fund. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 670 Fifth Avenue - Whitcomb, Assignment of Stock, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 145)
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Webb Property, 1913-1941 (Box 22, Folder 146)
    Purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Given to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1913. Abutted on John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s property. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. built commercial building to protect John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s light. Arbitration suit with one tenant. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Webb Property - Cartier Lease, 1912-1916 (Box 22, Folder 147)
    Not negotiated.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Webb Property - Cost of Building, 1913-1917 (Box 22, Folder 148)
    Summaries.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Webb Property - Eidlitz & Son, 1913-1917 (Box 22, Folder 149)
    Construction of building.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Webb Property - Bosworth Commission, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 150)
    Payment of architect fees.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue, 1941-1953 (Box 23, Folder 151)
    Maintenance of property. Sale of property in 1946. Correspondents include A. L. Chipman.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - A. Marchand, Inc., 1927-1945 (Box 23, Folder 152)
    Rental rates.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Alfred Orlik, 1944-1947 (Box 23, Folder 153)
    Rental arrangements.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Hammer Cooperage, 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 154)
    Preparation of space for occupancy.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - John F. Kroushaar, 1919-1948 (Box 23, Folder 155)
    Rent arrears. Compromise.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Bernard Weatherill, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 156)
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Nettie Rosenstein, Inc., 1942-1945 (Box 23, Folder 157)
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Maison Burans, 1936-1946 (Box 23, Folder 158)
    Rental Arrangement.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Yamanaka Lease, 1917-1940; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 159)
    Lease arrangements; government control after December 7, 1941. Alien Property Custodian operation; liquidation of firm. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, F. S. Staley, A. L. Chipman, Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Yamanaka Lease, 1941-1944; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 160)
  - New York Property - 684 Fifth Avenue - General, 1925-1945 (Box 23, Folder 161)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased Mrs. H. N. Twombly's home in order to protect his own home; paid $1,550,000 for the building and site. Management of building; proposed use of building; sale. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 684 Fifth Avenue - regarding Lease, 1926-1936; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 162)
  - New York Property - 684 Fifth Avenue - Regarding Lease, 1926-1936; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 163)
  - New York Property - 684 Fifth Avenue - Revillon Freres Lease, 1928-1946 (Box 23, Folder 164)
    Lease terms; readjustments; rent defaults. Copy of lease, modifying agreement. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. L. Chipman, F. S. Staley.
  - New York Property - 680 Fifth Avenue - Sale, 1945-1955 (Box 24, Folder 165)
    Sale to G. Jensen, Inc., in March, 1946. Terms; discussions; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. held first mortgage for balance of price. Extension of mortgage. Building resold; payment of mortgage by Canadian interests. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - New York Property - Fifth Avenue & 53rd Street - Sale to Tiffany, 1936-1939 (Box 24, Folder 166)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. owned the property, attempted to sell it to Tiffany. No result indicated in this envelope. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - Fifth Avenue & 55th Street - Gotham Hotel, 1927-1943 (Box 24, Folder 167)
    Repeated offerings of property to Rockefellers. The Rockefellers were not interested. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue - General, 1946-1950; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 168)
    Purchase of property by Laurance S. Rockefeller. He had an apartment in the house. Renting of apartments. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, R. B. Marston, Douglas Gibbons.
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue - General, 1946-1950 (Box 24, Folder 0168A)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue - General, 1951-1952; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 169)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue - Insurance, 1947-1957 (Box 24, Folder 170)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation, 1948-1951; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 24, Folder 171)
    Formation of a cooperative corporation to take over Laurance S. Rockefeller's investment in the building. Laurance S. Rockefeller became a member of the cooperative. Management of the building. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, R. B. Marston.
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation, 1952; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 24, Folder 172)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation, 1952-1954; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 25, Folder 173)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation, 1955-1961; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 25, Folder 174)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Douglas Gibbons & Company - Management Agreement, 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 175)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Mortgages, 1948-1953 (Box 25, Folder 176)
  - New York Property - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - Mortgages - City Investing Company, Correspondence, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 177)